<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hake Blog</title>
    <description>Adventures in web design.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 18:36:58 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 18:36:58 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Angular Store</title>
        <description>&lt;link href=&quot;https://maxcdn.bootstrapcdn.com/bootstrap/3.3.4/css/bootstrap.min.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/angularjs/1.3.14/angular.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;../assets/javascript/angular-store.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div ng-app=&quot;gemStore&quot; ng-controller=&quot;StoreController as store&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div  ng-repeat=&quot;product in store.products&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;product row&quot; ng-hide=&quot;store.product.soldOut&quot;&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;
		    	[[ product.name ]]
		    	&lt;em class=&quot;pull-right&quot;&gt;[[ product.price | currency ]]&lt;/em&gt;
			&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;button ng-show=&quot;product.canPurchase&quot;&gt;Add to cart&lt;/button&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot; ng-show=&quot;product.images.length&quot;&gt;
	        	&lt;img class=&quot;img img-circle img-thumbnail center-block&quot;  ng-src=&quot;[[ product.images[0] ]]&quot;/&gt;
        	
	        	&lt;ul class=&quot;img-thumbnails clearfix&quot;&gt;
			        &lt;li class=&quot;small-image pull-left thumbnail&quot; ng-repeat=&quot;image in product.images&quot;&gt;
			            &lt;img ng-src=&quot;[[image]]&quot; /&gt;
		        	&lt;/li&gt;
		        &lt;/ul&gt;
	        &lt;/div&gt;

	        &lt;!-- Start the tab section. --&gt;
	        &lt;section class=&quot;tab&quot; ng-controller=&quot;TabController as tabController&quot;&gt;
		        
		        &lt;!-- Display tabs with product information listed using directives. --&gt;
		        &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
			    	&lt;li ng-class=&quot;{ active: tabController.isSet(1) }&quot;&gt;
			    		&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; ng-click=&quot;tabController.setTab(1)&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			    	&lt;li ng-class=&quot;{ active: tabController.isSet(2) }&quot;&gt;
			    		&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; ng-click=&quot;tabController.setTab(2)&quot;&gt;Specs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			    	&lt;li ng-class=&quot;{ active: tabController.isSet(3) }&quot;&gt;
			        	&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; ng-click=&quot;tabController.setTab(3)&quot;&gt;Reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			    &lt;/ul&gt;

			    &lt;!-- Display some attributes of the product when the tabs are clicked. --&gt;
			    &lt;!-- Display the product description. --&gt;
			    &lt;div ng-show=&quot;tabController.isSet(1)&quot;&gt;
			    	&lt;h4&gt;Description&lt;/h4&gt;
			    	&lt;blockquote&gt;[[ product.description ]]&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			    &lt;/div&gt;

			    &lt;!-- Display the shine value of the product. --&gt;
			    &lt;div ng-show=&quot;tabController.isSet(2)&quot;&gt;
			    	&lt;h4&gt;Specs&lt;/h4&gt;
			    	&lt;blockquote&gt;Shine: [[ product.shine ]]&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			    &lt;/div&gt;

		    	&lt;!-- Display the reviews of previous customers. --&gt;
			    &lt;div ng-show=&quot;tabController.isSet(3)&quot;&gt;
			    	&lt;ul&gt;
            			&lt;h4&gt;Reviews&lt;/h4&gt;
            			&lt;!-- Simple loop through the reiviews - link the data from the loop &quot;review&quot; object. --&gt;
            			&lt;li ng-repeat=&quot;review in product.reviews&quot;&gt;
            				&lt;blockquote&gt;
                				&lt;strong&gt;[[ review.stars ]] Stars&lt;/strong&gt;
                  				[[ review.body ]]
                				&lt;cite class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;—[[ review.author ]]&lt;/cite&gt;
                			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
              			&lt;/li&gt;
            		&lt;/ul&gt;
 
            		&lt;!--Within this form, import the review controller and add the submit function, which will push
            		the new review onto the reviews array. --&gt;
	            	&lt;form name=&quot;reviewForm&quot; ng-controller=&quot;ReviewController as reviewCtrl&quot;
	            		ng-submit=&quot;reviewCtrl.addReview(product)&quot;&gt;
	            		&lt;!--  Review submit form with live preview using ng-model to link data. --&gt;
		            	&lt;!--  Live Preview --&gt;
		            	&lt;h4&gt;Preview:&lt;/h4&gt;
			            &lt;blockquote&gt;
			            	&lt;strong&gt;[[reviewCtrl.review.stars]] Stars&lt;/strong&gt;
			                [[reviewCtrl.review.body]]
			                &lt;cite class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;—[[reviewCtrl.review.author]]&lt;/cite&gt;
		            	&lt;/blockquote&gt;

		            	&lt;!-- The model is prefixed with the reviewCtrl controller, which handles the pushing. --&gt;
			            &lt;h4&gt;Submit a Review&lt;/h4&gt;
			            &lt;fieldset class=&quot;form-group&quot;&gt;
			            	&lt;select ng-model=&quot;reviewCtrl.review.stars&quot; class=&quot;form-control&quot; ng-options=&quot;stars for stars in [5,4,3,2,1]&quot;	title=&quot;Stars&quot;&gt;
			                	&lt;option value=&quot;&quot;&gt;Rate the Product&lt;/option&gt;
			                &lt;/select&gt;
			            &lt;/fieldset&gt;
			            &lt;fieldset class=&quot;form-group&quot;&gt;
			                &lt;textarea ng-model=&quot;reviewCtrl.review.body&quot; class=&quot;form-control&quot; placeholder=&quot;Write a short review of the product...&quot; title=&quot;Review&quot;&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;
			            &lt;/fieldset&gt;
			            &lt;fieldset class=&quot;form-group&quot;&gt;
			                &lt;input ng-model=&quot;reviewCtrl.review.author&quot; type=&quot;email&quot; class=&quot;form-control&quot; placeholder=&quot;jimmyDean@example.org&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot; /&gt;
			            &lt;/fieldset&gt;
			            &lt;fieldset class=&quot;form-group&quot;&gt;
			                &lt;input type=&quot;submit&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary pull-right&quot; value=&quot;Submit Review&quot; /&gt;
			            &lt;/fieldset&gt;
		            &lt;/form&gt;
			    &lt;/div&gt;
      		&lt;/section&gt;

		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 16:45:21 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/angular-store</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/angular-store</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 3.5</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve finished the majority of the portfolio site I have been working on.  As I finish it off I will host it over at [BuntingfordComputing.co.uk][buntingfordcomputing.co.uk], the domain and host I use as a test bed for new sites I create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s set up as a single page app, which utilises some simple jQuery AJAX calls to display the extra information the user requests (specific project and client info).  The site uses SASS and the SASS extension Bourbon for styling, which has been a lot easier to use than css, especially when it comes to animations and the +clearfix function!  I will definitely use SASS whenever I can in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to focus on quantity rather than quality up to a point with this Jekyll sites.  So I am going to finish this one up and establish some areas which are lacking, before moving on to a new site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main areas which are weak in this portfolio site are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Positioning of SVG elements, such as the logos (which I just cut in the end) and the emblems for the youtube page and website.  I just couldn’t get the absolute positioning to work, the SVG elements just dissapeared when I used it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using 3rd party content such as animations from [BounceJS][http://bouncejs.com/] or textures from [MakerBook][http://makerbook.net/].  I kept the animations preliminarily css and stock jQuery this time to keep my finish time down to ao minumum.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating and using proper Bourbon mix-ins to save my recoding time. For instance, creating a mixin for the default font size/colour/weight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Properly utilising liquid script’s loops and logic to simplifiy my HTML.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The yml settings file.  I need to allow more settings to be set here and accessed with liquid in the markup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 16:46:21 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/week-3.1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/week-3.1</guid>
        
        
        <category>weekly</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What I was trying to avoid has happened; my side projects have reverted to dribs and drabs of work again.  The two weeks of one page a day went well but, I quickly ran out of smaller ideas and moved onto larger ones which have become disjointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I started work on a second Jekyll site (after creating this one) which uses sass and a css library I haven’t used before called bourbon.  I created the site to showcase an artists portfolio and I have learned a lot about the design aspect of web-design in the process, coming from a solely programming background is was almost all new to me.  I plan to finish the site and get it hosted tomorrow, it will become the first of many I will be able to showcase if I turn my hand to freelance web-design in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next week I want to start creating smaller javascript apps again to keep my hand in with jQuery and Angular.  I’d like to create a small store page with JSON data displayed with Angular controllers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the week I will move back to the design aspect and complete a few tutorials I have found for some of the more complex aesthetics I have seen around the web.  These will hopefully include the paralax effect and some more fiddly sass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the backburner I need to work out how to properly host a ruby on rails app with cPanel.  It’s a bit ridiculous that I can now create a fully function ruby on rails application, but I can’t host it on anything other than the painfully slow heroku free service.  I must be overthinking it because I know it can be done, I just havent read enough yet… Once I get it up and running on my faster server, I’ll be able to get my teeth into persistent data and much more interesting apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;checklist-for-the-week-of-1852015&quot;&gt;Checklist for the week of 18/5/2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Host the portfolio site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic Angular store app&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More complex sass Jekyll site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Host RoR apps with cPanel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 16:46:21 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/week-3</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/week-3</guid>
        
        
        <category>weekly</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week centred around the creation of a few more jQuery apps, testing out Angular with a simple one page app, and the prototype of a small javascript library I would like to publish named Twilight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started the week with three more slightly more complex canvas apps, which incorporated collisions and some more complex maths.  This is nothing I haven’t dealt with before, but I feel like the correct pacing while learning Javascript/jQuery will make me aware of more of their intricacies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I found the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ss-hake.github.io/pages/particlesTest.html&quot;&gt;Particles.js&lt;/a&gt; library, which really opened my eyes to how easy it was to create a useful and interesting library with javascript, so I began work on my own this week. &lt;a href=&quot;http://ss-hake.github.io/pages/twilight.html&quot;&gt;Twilight.js&lt;/a&gt; is still in the early stages but I have created the basis for an active background which simulates a warm summers evening (inspired by the evening of the 19th April 2015) using a canvas element.  The background features randomly generated twinkling stars and planets of various sizes, as well as randomly generated, animated planes and satellites which move accross the sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While working on Twilight.js towards the end of the week I also completed my goals from last week’s post by testing AngularJS with a simple app which displays different information through interaction with different HTML elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goals for next week are to add random shooting stars to Twilight.js as well as adding support for an initialisation file which sets different variables such as plane and satellite frequency and the background colour of the canvas.  Once that is complete, some final tweaking is all that will be required before publication of my first Javascript library on Github!  Once that is complete I will be able to focus more on my AngularJS development and start looking at methods to incorporate persistent data into my apps, allowing for the development of more useful apps like shopping lists, etc!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hours logged: 15.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 16:46:21 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/week-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/week-2</guid>
        
        
        <category>weekly</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First published: 18/04/15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it’s the end of my first week.  I wanted to spend this week getting used to web development again, creating a few apps which just selected some elements and did something with them. The most basic concept of jQuery is to &lt;a href=&quot;http://learn.jquery.com/using-jquery-core/selecting-elements/&quot;&gt;“select some elements and do something with them”&lt;/a&gt;, so jQuery seemed like a good starting point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve made 6 apps so far, I started with a very simple script which handled the cursor entering a large selection of square divs I had created manually by copy-pasting HTML elements.  I ended the week with an app which uses a wrapper library on top of jQuery to automate the generation and animation of 1000 divs, I’m quite happy with that progression.  Along the way, I’ve been re-learning the basic concepts of Javascript and learning a lot more about jQuery, as well as little tips and tricks I hadn’t heard before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first of these tips was to use CDNs (Content Delivery Networks) to host my Javascript libraries. I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://encosia.com/3-reasons-why-you-should-let-google-host-jquery-for-you/&quot;&gt;this interesting post&lt;/a&gt; which extolled the virtues of letting &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/speed/libraries/&quot;&gt;Google host your libraries for you&lt;/a&gt;.  Adding the little tag pointing to the hosts library, rather than a copy I am hosting, results in faster loading times, cross-site caching and when I get around to using them; benefits when using AJAX calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other tips and tricks cropped up as I was reading through the jQuery documentation. Things like &lt;a href=&quot;http://learn.jquery.com/performance/append-outside-loop/&quot;&gt;appending outside of loops&lt;/a&gt; to increase performance and reduce computationally costly DOM insertion.  Or, using #ID and element selectors where ever possible, due to the fact that they are based on native DOM operations, which reduce search space that using attribute or pseudo might entail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next week I plan to expand my usage of underscore and put out some more complex jQuery apps.  I’ve also found a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/VincentGarreau/particles.js/&quot;&gt;cool library&lt;/a&gt; for making particles I’d like to try out, so one of the week’s apps will probably involve that (although I will be forced to host it myself!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hours logged: 12.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 16:45:21 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/week-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/week-1</guid>
        
        
        <category>weekly</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hake Blog v2.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new Hake Blog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve finally upgraded to a content management system; Jekyll.  I had been looking at other CMSs for a while but none of them seemed that applicable to a site of this size and structure.  I have used Ruby on Rails and Wordpress before, but they seemed too bukly for use on this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose Jekyll for a number of reasons including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extreme simplicity; the clean syntax and Angular-esque loops&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No database, which means faster loading&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple markdown syntax for content&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compatibility with Github Hosting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll essentially generates the same static pages that I was writing, but increases writing speed by building the pages from pre-written code modules. This all comes without the need for dynamic hosting, which is a requirement for Wordpress and the like.  Plus, there is always the option to extend with Disqus or a new theme in the future if I do want to add some interactivity or change the look of the site completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next 24 hours I’ll set up a custom theme for the site and import my old projects and blog posts.  Once this time is invested, adding new content should become very easy indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 18:56:31 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/updated-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/updated-blog.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Twilight</title>
        <description>&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;../assets/css/twilight.css&quot;&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;http://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/1.9.1/jquery.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;../assets/javascript/twilight.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
	&lt;canvas id=&quot;canvas&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot;&gt;

	&lt;/canvas&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 16:45:21 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/twilight</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/twilight</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Angular Test</title>
        <description>&lt;script src=&quot;http://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/1.9.1/jquery.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/angularjs/1.3.14/angular.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;../assets/javascript/angular-test.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;content&quot; ng-app=&quot;app&quot;&gt;

	First Name:&lt;input ng-model=&quot;firstName&quot; type=&quot;text&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;br&gt;
	Last Name:&lt;input ng-model=&quot;lastName&quot; type=&quot;text&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;br&gt;
	Greetings, [[firstName]] [[lastName]]!

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 16:45:21 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/angular-test</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/angular-test</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Particles Test</title>
        <description>&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;../assets/css/particles-test.css&quot;&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;http://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/1.9.1/jquery.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;../assets/javascript/particles.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;../assets/javascript/particles-test.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;particles-js&quot;&gt;
				
				
				
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 16:45:21 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/particles-test</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/particles-test</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Canvas Clock</title>
        <description>&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;../assets/css/canvas-clock.css&quot;&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;http://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/1.9.1/jquery.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;../assets/javascript/canvas-clock.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
	&lt;canvas id=&quot;canvas&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; width=&quot;550&quot;&gt;

	&lt;/canvas&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 16:45:21 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/canvas-clock</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/canvas-clock</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
